Tanmayi Patel

+1(226)881-2486 | tanmayipatel12@gmail.com | Kitchener, ON, CA www.linkedin.com/in/tanmayi-patel/

Professional Summary

Resourceful Senior Web Developer with experience of 4+ years in website and application creation. Insightful when supervising complex web planning, designing, development, implementation, and testing stages. Extensive support for leading teams generating source code, regardless of necessitated programming language.

Professional Experience

Software Developer, Pocketride Inc., Sarnia, Ontario, Canada

January 2024 - Present

- Creating platform visually stunning and highly functional digital designs in Figma.
- Integrating wireframes, prototypes, and design systems, ensuring consistency and scalability across projects.
- Developed custom animation libraries and design systems within Figma, streamlining the animation workflow and promoting consistency across projects.

Senior Web Developer, SASA Infotech, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

February 2021 - July 2022

- Created websites using JavaScript (React. js, Node. js), CSS, HTML, PHP, and other programming languages.
- Enhanced default features with more compatibility to amplify user experiences.
- Worked on scalable environments in Agile/SCRUM methodologies. Prepare Test Cases using TDD (test-driven development).
- Built RESTful APIs using popular frameworks such as Express.js Rest Framework.
- Completed day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently and managed a team as a leader.

Web Application Developer, WeeTech Solutions PVT LTD, Surat, Gujarat, India August 2019-December 2020

- Developed and implemented new features for web applications using PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, and RESTful web services using the Laravel framework.
- Implemented websites with RESTful APIs and added more reliable features.
- Deployed updated versions of websites using FTP or SSH tools after testing them thoroughly.
- Provided end-user training on content management systems so that employees could easily maintain and update the website without help from developers.

Industrial Training IT Student, The Imaginations, Surat, Gujarat, India December 2018-May 2019

- Provided technical support to users experiencing issues with websites.
- Collaborate with clients on-site to review their websites and make modifications per their requirements.
- Supported staff activities to assist web page launches and meetings with clients.

Intern, D&K group of companies, Surat, Gujarat, India

May 2018-June 2018

- Learned and developed web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.
- Collaborated with senior developers to design and implement features within MVC frameworks, contributing to developing dynamic and interactive user interfaces.

Technical Skills

- JavaScript (Node.js, React.js, TypeScript, Express, Vue.js).
- PHP (Laravel/CodeIgniter/CakePHP/AJAX)
- HTML / HTML5
- MySQL, MongoDB
- Cascading Style Sheets (CSS, CSS3), Bootstrap, Figma
- Unit testing, Open-source platforms, Agile development
- GitHub, GitLab
- MERN stack development
- Jira, Trello, Asana, Slack

Education

Post-graduation

Web Development, Conestoga College, Waterloo, ON September 2022 - December 2023

Bachelor of Technology

Information Technology, C.G.P.I.T, Uka Tarsadia University, Bardoli, Surat June 2015 - May 2019

References

Ansh Bhutani

Founder and CEO of Pocketride Inc. Sarnia, ON, Canada <u>anshbhutani1996@gmail.com</u> <u>pocketrideofficial@gmail.com</u>

Yash Budheliya

Co-Founder and CFO of Pocketride Inc. Sarnia, ON, Canada budheliya.yash17@gmail.com +1 (226) 886-3824

Chamanvir Kaur

Co-Founder and CTO of Pocketride Inc. Sarnia, ON, Canada camk.93@gmail.com +1 (548) 883-2104